[
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- The song Police State by the political hip-hop group Dead Prez appeared on what landmark 2000 album?",
        "correct": "Lets Get Free",
        "answerA": "Lets Get Free",
        "answerB": "RBG: Revolutionary but Gangsta",
        "answerC": "Information Age",
        "answerD": "Wake Up!"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- The New Jersey based \"Juice Crew\" rapper Queen Latifah dropped this powerful song in 1993 pushing back against all of the disrespect aimed at women and girls in Hip-Hop. ",
        "correct": "\"U.N.I.T.Y.\"",
        "answerA": "\"U.N.I.T.Y.\"",
        "answerB": "\"Black Infinity\"",
        "answerC": "\"You're a Black Women\"",
        "answerD": "\"Who You Calling a Bitch?\""
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS-  Eminem performed a scathing  freestyle rap attack against this politician and any of his fans who support him in October 2017. Who was the politician?",
        "correct": "Donald Trump",
        "answerA": "Donald Trump",
        "answerB": "Hillary Clinton",
        "answerC": "Joe Biden",
        "answerD": "Barack Obama"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- Killer Mike, political rapper and hip-hop activist based in Atlanta, Georgia endorsed which presidential candidate in 2016?",
        "correct": "Bernie Sanders",
        "answerA": "Bernie Sanders",
        "answerB": "Michelle Obama",
        "answerC": "Joe Biden",
        "answerD": "Jill Stein"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- This seminal hip- hop group was responsible for popularizing socially conscious hip-hop in the early 1980's with classics like \"the Message\" and \"New York, New York.\"",
        "correct": "Grand Master Flash & the Furious 5",
        "answerA": "Grand Master Flash & the Furious 5",
        "answerB": "The Treacherous Three",
        "answerC": "Run DMC",
        "answerD": "The Sugar Hill Gang"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- J. Cole's \"High for Hours,\" released in early 2017, mentioned a meeting with which president?",
        "correct": "Barack Obama",
        "answerA": "Barack Obama",
        "answerB": "Donald Trump",
        "answerC": "George W Bush",
        "answerD": "Bill Clinton"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- This Oakland area based, radical hip-hop artist implored black people to \"Break the Grip of Shame\" in a 1990 hip-hip song. Who was the artist?",
        "correct": "Paris",
        "answerA": "Paris",
        "answerB": "Mac Dre",
        "answerC": "E-40",
        "answerD": "Too Short"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- This white, Seattle based, hip-hop artist wrote and performed the song \"Same Love\", which condemns homophobia in hip-hop.",
        "correct": "Macklemore",
        "answerA": "Macklemore",
        "answerB": "Onry Ozzborn",
        "answerC": "LL Cool J",
        "answerD": "MC Search"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- This neo hip-hop song off the Digable Planets 1993 debut album Reachin' (A New Refutation of Time and Space) stands up for reproductive freedom for women.",
        "correct": "\"La Femme Fetal\"",
        "answerA": "\"La Femme Fetal\"",
        "answerB": "\"Where I'm From\"",
        "answerC": "\"Rebirth of Slick (Cool Like Dat)\"",
        "answerD": "\"Nickel Bags\""
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- The UK rapper Slowthai released this album in 2019 with songs critical of Brexit and Theresa May.",
        "correct": "Nothing Great About Britain",
        "answerA": "Nothing Great About Britain",
        "answerB": "This Ain't England",
        "answerC": "I Wish I Knew",
        "answerD": "God Made the Queen"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- Which list of artists were all part of the political rap-rock \"super group\" Prophets of Rage? ",
        "correct": "Jim Commerford, Tom Morello, Brad Wilk, DJ Lord, Chuck D, and B-Real",
        "answerA": "Jim Commerford, Tom Morello, Brad Wilk, DJ Lord, Chuck D, and B-Real",
        "answerB": "Brad Wilk, DJ Lord, Chuck D, B-Real and Snoop Dogg",
        "answerC": "Tom Morello, Brad Wilk, DJ Lord, Chuck D, B-Real and Ice Cube",
        "answerD": "Tim Commerford, Tom Morello, Brad Wilk, and Flea"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- This rapper was visited by the Secret Service in 2018 in response to alleged threatening lyrics towards Donald Trump in his song  \"The Ringer.\" ",
        "correct": "Eminem",
        "answerA": "Eminem",
        "answerB": "Snoop Dogg",
        "answerC": "Tim Dog",
        "answerD": "Ice Cube"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- The hip hop artist Ice Cube pulled together and produced this LA based black nationalist rap group named after his record label.",
        "correct": "Da Lynch Mob",
        "answerA": "Da Lynch Mob",
        "answerB": "WC and the Maad Circle",
        "answerC": "EPMD",
        "answerD": "Westside Connection"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- The angry screed \"Black Cop\" by KRS-One appeared on what album? ",
        "correct": "Return of the Boom Bap",
        "answerA": "Return of the Boom Bap",
        "answerB": "By All Means Necessary",
        "answerC": "Criminal Minded",
        "answerD": "I Got Next"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- The East Bay radical political hip- hop artist Paris invited this New York based rapper on an extended mix track of the song \"Field Nigga Boogie\" off his 2003 album Sonic Jihad. ",
        "correct": "Immortal Technique",
        "answerA": "Immortal Technique",
        "answerB": "Slick Rick",
        "answerC": "LL Cool J",
        "answerD": "Master P"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- The American rapper and political activist Talib Kweli teamed up with Mos Def in 1997 to form this influential hip-hop group.",
        "correct": "Black Star",
        "answerA": "Black Star",
        "answerB": "Wu-Tang Clan",
        "answerC": "Black Sheep",
        "answerD": "Onyx"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- In the 1993 Cypress Hill song \"I Want to Get High\" which politician did the group encourage to \"go and inhale?\" ",
        "correct": "Bill Clinton",
        "answerA": "Bill Clinton",
        "answerB": "John Edwards",
        "answerC": "Gary Hart",
        "answerD": "Al Gore"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- LA based hip-hop artist and community activist Nipsey Hussle was murdered in March 2019. How old was he?",
        "correct": "33",
        "answerA": "33",
        "answerB": "27",
        "answerC": "53",
        "answerD": "19"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- The Root's 4th studio album Things Fall Apart took its name from a 1958 book from which political Nigerian writer?",
        "correct": "Chinua Achebe",
        "answerA": "Chinua Achebe",
        "answerB": "Kwame Nkrumah",
        "answerC": "Wole Soyinka",
        "answerD": "Franz Fanon"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- Afrika Bambaataa, widely considered the creator of electro- funk and an influential hip- hop innovator, founded what South Bronx based hip- hop organization in 1973",
        "correct": "The Universal Zulu Nation",
        "answerA": "The Universal Zulu Nation",
        "answerB": "Boogie Down Productions",
        "answerC": "Hip Hop Congress",
        "answerD": "Hip Hop for Change"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- Jay- Z has funded a number of social causes including this group dedicated to criminal justice reform. What's the name of the organization?",
        "correct": "Reform Alliance",
        "answerA": "Reform Alliance",
        "answerB": "Prison Abolition Committee",
        "answerC": "Criminal Justice Task Force",
        "answerD": "End Mass Incarceration Now!"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- This Dr. Dre protégé came out in support of Colin Kaepernick and his symbolic protest against police brutality at the BET Hip-Hop Awards in 2017.",
        "correct": "Eminem",
        "answerA": "Eminem",
        "answerB": "Snoop Dogg",
        "answerC": "Easy E",
        "answerD": "DJ Yella"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- MMG was a Revolutionary Communist Party affiliated hip-hop collective from New York that recorded this pro-U.S. flag burning song back in 1990.",
        "correct": "\"Burn Baby Burn\"",
        "answerA": "\"Burn Baby Burn\"",
        "answerB": "\"50 State Fire\"",
        "answerC": "\"Old Glory in Flames\"",
        "answerD": "\"Burn the Flag\""
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- Which Vice President went on TV to attack Tupac Shakar's first album 2pacalypse Now in 1991 blaming it for a police officer's death in Texas.",
        "correct": "Dan Quayle",
        "answerA": "Dan Quayle",
        "answerB": "Nelson Rockefeller",
        "answerC": "Dick Cheney",
        "answerD": "Al Gore"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- On March 18 2016, 13 swat team members with the Fayetteville police department raided this rappers recording studio in North Carolina. Who was it?",
        "correct": "J. Cole",
        "answerA": "J. Cole",
        "answerB": "21 Savage",
        "answerC": "Drake",
        "answerD": "Kendrick Lamar"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- Which Black nationalist poetry group appeared on the A Tribe Called Quest song  \"Excursions\" off their 1991 masterpiece The Low End Theory? ",
        "correct": "The Last Poets",
        "answerA": "The Last Poets",
        "answerB": "The Black Kings",
        "answerC": "The Black Notes",
        "answerD": "The Last Negros"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- What was the name of the anti-violence song that the West Coast Rap All-Stars dropped in 1990?",
        "correct": "\"We're All in the Same Gang\"",
        "answerA": "\"We're All in the Same Gang\"",
        "answerB": "\"No Justice, Just Us\"",
        "answerC": "\"They Just See Black\"",
        "answerD": "\"Stop Killing Your Brothers\""
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- In 2017 this Muslim rapper from Flint, Michigan released a song defending women who choose to wear Hijabs called \"Hijabi (Wrap my Hijab).\" What's her name?",
        "correct": "Mona Hayder",
        "answerA": "Mona Hayder",
        "answerB": "Mayam Mahmoud",
        "answerC": "Shadia Mansour",
        "answerD": "Felukah"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- Bronx based, female rapper Cardi B endorsed this candidate for president in 2020.",
        "correct": "Bernie Sanders",
        "answerA": "Bernie Sanders",
        "answerB": "Elizabeth Warren",
        "answerC": "Andrew Yang",
        "answerD": "Kamala Harris"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- What's the name of the Philadelphia based alternative hip-hop group The Goats second album?",
        "correct": "No Goats, No Glory",
        "answerA": "No Goats, No Glory",
        "answerB": "Tricks of the Shade",
        "answerC": "Typical American",
        "answerD": "Rumblefish"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- The song \"Self Destruction,\" a late '80's rap song that spoke out against black on black violence, was created by the Stop the Violence Movement. Who started it?",
        "correct": "KRS-One",
        "answerA": "KRS-One",
        "answerB": "George Clinton",
        "answerC": "Chuck D",
        "answerD": "Afrika Bambaataa"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- This member of the groundbreaking New York hip-hop group the Fugees decided to return to their birthplace, Haiti, in 2010 and run for president.",
        "correct": "Wyclef Jean",
        "answerA": "Wyclef Jean",
        "answerB": "Pras Michel",
        "answerC": "Lauryn Hill",
        "answerD": "Chris Schwartz"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- Jay-Z called out Al Sharpton in this hip-hop track for scapegoating rap music for promoting negative stereotypes of urban blacks.",
        "correct": "\"Say Hello\"",
        "answerA": "\"Say Hello\"",
        "answerB": "\"99 Problems\"",
        "answerC": "\"Drop it Like its Hot\"",
        "answerD": "\"Frontin'\""
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- The late Lumumba Carson, better known as Professor X the Overseer, was a black nationalist, Brooklyn based rapper with what group in the late 1980's and early 90's?",
        "correct": "X-Clan",
        "answerA": "X-Clan",
        "answerB": "Poor Righteous Teachers",
        "answerC": "Brand Nubian",
        "answerD": "The Last Poets"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- Hip-Hop artist Jay-Z endorsed this political leader for president in 2008.",
        "correct": "Barack Obama",
        "answerA": "Barack Obama",
        "answerB": "John Edwards",
        "answerC": "Alan Keyes",
        "answerD": "Hillary Clinton"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- Ice Cube's second album, an incendiary black nationalist, hip-hop classic,  debuted at number one on the Billboard charts. What was it?",
        "correct": "Death Certificate",
        "answerA": "Death Certificate",
        "answerB": "War and Peace Volume 1",
        "answerC": "The Predator",
        "answerD": "Amerikkka's Most Wanted"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- The famous film maker Spike Lee partnered with this political hip-hip group in the late 1980's to produce the main song- \"Fight the Power\"- in the sound track to his movie Do the Right Thing. ",
        "correct": "Public Enemy",
        "answerA": "Public Enemy",
        "answerB": "Run-DMC",
        "answerC": "Paris",
        "answerD": "X-Clan"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- The southern rap artist Lil Wayne wrote the song \"Georgia Bush\" in 2007 in response to what event?",
        "correct": "Hurricane Katrina",
        "answerA": "Hurricane Katrina",
        "answerB": "The mass shooting at Fort Hood",
        "answerC": "The surge of combat troops in Iraq",
        "answerD": "The Georgia Tech mass shooting"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- How many pages did the FBI have on Tupac Shakar right before his death?",
        "correct": "4,000",
        "answerA": "4,000",
        "answerB": "7,800",
        "answerC": "200",
        "answerD": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- The hip-Hop artist Common wrote \"A Song for Assata\" in 2000. Assata Shakur was a member of what black liberation organization of the 1970's and 80's?",
        "correct": "Black Liberation Army",
        "answerA": "Black Liberation Army",
        "answerB": "Blackstone Rangers",
        "answerC": "Nation of Islam",
        "answerD": "Black Panther Party"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- This former member of the Geto Boys wrote the song \"Fuck Rodney King\" in response to King's timid reaction to the not guilty verdicts related to his own brutal beating by the police",
        "correct": "Willie D",
        "answerA": "Willie D",
        "answerB": "Bushwick Bill",
        "answerC": "Master P",
        "answerD": "Scarface"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- The song Steve Biko (Stir it Up) by A Tribe Called Quest appeared on what 1993 album of theirs?",
        "correct": "Midnight Marauders",
        "answerA": "Midnight Marauders",
        "answerB": "The Love Movement",
        "answerC": "The Low End Theory",
        "answerD": "Beats Rhymes & Life"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- The 1991 rap hit \"Free South Africa\" appeared on which Stetsasonic album? ",
        "correct": "Blood, Sweat and no Tears",
        "answerA": "Blood, Sweat and no Tears",
        "answerB": "Just Say Stet",
        "answerC": "In Full Gear",
        "answerD": "On Fire"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- This feminist, sex positive, hip-hop trio won a Grammy for the 1995 song \"None of Your Business.\"",
        "correct": "Salt-N-Pepa",
        "answerA": "Salt-N-Pepa",
        "answerB": "The Mercedes Ladies",
        "answerC": "Destiny's Child",
        "answerD": "SWV"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- Members of Public Enemy and Rage Against the Machine got together with this LA based hip-hop group in 2007 to create the group Prophets of Rage.",
        "correct": "Cypress Hill",
        "answerA": "Cypress Hill",
        "answerB": "Ozomatli",
        "answerC": "Da Lynch Mob",
        "answerD": "Dilated Peoples"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- The Arrested Development song \"Revolution\" appeared on what 1992 album? ",
        "correct": "The soundtrack to the movie Malcolm X",
        "answerA": "The soundtrack to the movie Malcolm X",
        "answerB": "The soundtrack to the movie Menace II Society",
        "answerC": "The soundtrack to the movie Black Panther",
        "answerD": "The soundtrack to the movie Boyz in the Hood"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- This Denver based indy hip- hop anarchist released the 2013 album No Wising Up, No Settling Down in which he declared \"I Think I'm Emma Goldman.\"",
        "correct": "Sole",
        "answerA": "Sole",
        "answerB": "Macklemore",
        "answerC": "J. Cole",
        "answerD": "emcee lynx"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- What year was the classic reality rap song \"The Message\" by Grand Master Flash and the Furious Five released? ",
        "correct": "1981",
        "answerA": "1981",
        "answerB": "1973",
        "answerC": "2011",
        "answerD": "2005"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- The Peruvian American political hip-hop artist Immortal Technique appeared in this movie drama about the 2004 Republican National Convention in New York City.",
        "correct": "This Revolution",
        "answerA": "This Revolution",
        "answerB": "My Revolution",
        "answerC": "Revolution Now",
        "answerD": "Our Revolution"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- What Bronx based political rapper started the label Boogie Down Productions with the late Scott La Rock?",
        "correct": "KRS-One",
        "answerA": "KRS-One",
        "answerB": "Kool Moe Dee",
        "answerC": "Nas",
        "answerD": "Kool G Rap"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- This US based rapper was the first female, solo, hip-hop artist to release a full rap album in 1988. Who is she?",
        "correct": "MC Lyte",
        "answerA": "MC Lyte",
        "answerB": "The Lady of Rage",
        "answerC": "Queen Latifah",
        "answerD": "Yo-Yo"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- This Philadelphia based hip hop artist who got trapped in Pennsylvania's criminal justice system based on a wrongful arrest at 19, started the Reform Alliance with Jay Z.",
        "correct": "Meek Mill",
        "answerA": "Meek Mill",
        "answerB": "Schoolly D",
        "answerC": "Steady B",
        "answerD": "Black Thought"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- What was the underling point of Tupac Shakur's \"Thug Life\" philosophy? ",
        "correct": "To politicize black street gangs across the US",
        "answerA": "To politicize black street gangs across the US",
        "answerB": "To unite all motorcycle gangs across all races",
        "answerC": "To encourage friendship between Blacks and Latinos",
        "answerD": "To encourage blacks to start their own businesses"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- Which record label first distributed the conscious hip-hop and world music artist Michael Franti?",
        "correct": "Alternative Tentacles",
        "answerA": "Alternative Tentacles",
        "answerB": "Anti-",
        "answerC": "Six Degrees Records",
        "answerD": "Capitol"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- Black America Again, released in 2016, was the 11th studio album by which political hip-hop artist?",
        "correct": "Common",
        "answerA": "Common",
        "answerB": "Drake",
        "answerC": "Usher",
        "answerD": "John Legend"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- Sinead O Conner teamed up with this rap artist in 1988 for the sex positive song  \"I Want Your (Hands on Me.)\" ",
        "correct": "MC Lyte",
        "answerA": "MC Lyte",
        "answerB": "Left Eye (Lisa Lopes)",
        "answerC": "Missy Elliott",
        "answerD": "Monie Love"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- Poor Righteous Teachers, a socially conscious hip-hop group big in the late 80's and 90's, were a part of what New York based soci-spiritual movement?",
        "correct": "The Five Percent Nation",
        "answerA": "The Five Percent Nation",
        "answerB": "The Three Percent Nation",
        "answerC": "The 10 Percent Nation",
        "answerD": "The One Percent Nation"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- Afrika Bambaataa teamed up with former Sex Pistols singer Johnny Lydon in 1984 to record the anti-fascist, anti-racist classic \"World Destruction.\" What was the name of their group?",
        "correct": "Time Zone",
        "answerA": "Time Zone",
        "answerB": "War Zone",
        "answerC": "Fight Zone",
        "answerD": "Death Zone"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- Lauryn Hill performed the song \"I Find it Hard to Say (Rebel)\" in a memorable performance on which show in 2002?",
        "correct": "MTV Unplugged",
        "answerA": "MTV Unplugged",
        "answerB": "In Living Color",
        "answerC": "Saturday Night Live",
        "answerD": "The Arsenio Hall Show"
    },
    {
        "question": "REBEL RAPPERS- What's the name East Bay rapper Paris's first album?",
        "correct": "The Devil Made Me Do It",
        "answerA": "The Devil Made Me Do It",
        "answerB": "Sonic Jihad",
        "answerC": "Sleeping With the Enemy",
        "answerD": "Acid Reflex"
    }
]